<resources>
    <string name="app_name">GoPink!</string>

    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_example_testimony">ExampleTestimony</string>
    <string name="title_activity_early_intervention">Early Intervention</string>
    <string name="title_activity_living_breast">Living with Breast Cancer</string>
    <string name="title_activity_metastasis">Recurrence/Metastasis</string>
    <string name="title_activity_prevention">Prevention is the Cure!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_survivors">Breast Cancer Survivors</string>

    <string name="norie">Norie G. Aguilo -\nAbnormal thermal breast imaging at age 26\n\n\t
Born on 4 August 1977 in Manila, her menarche was at age 13. Norie noticed a lump on her left breast at age 23. Not wanting any invasive means of breast screening, she underwent a thermal imaging of her breasts two years later, which showed an abnormal pattern on the supero-lateral aspect of her left breast. By pursuing non-toxic and non-surgical interventions, she is very hopeful in preserving her breasts and living a life of vitality and wellness. </string>
    <string name="placida">Placida C. Babao  -\nAbnormal thermal breast imaging at age 63\n\n\t
Born on 5 October 1940 in Batangas City, her menarche was at age 13. She was prescribed HRT at age 53 for her menopause and 1o years later noticed a lump in her right breast with pain on her left breast. A widow with 5 children, she underwent thermal breast imaging which saw an abnormal right breast. She then went to the PBCN and months later, did a repeat thermal which now showed both her breasts to be normal.</string>
    <string name="marivic">Marivic N. Belleza -\nAbnormal thermal breast imaging at age 43\n\n\t
Born on 1 February 1962 in Tigbauan, Iloilo, her menarche was at age 14. A Bachelor of Laws graduate, Marivic now resides in Bacolod City and works as the Finance Officer of a construction company. At age 42, she felt lumps in her right armpit. She underwent thermal imaging in March 2006, which showed an abnormal pattern on her right breast. She underwent a non-toxic and non-invasive regimen and thereafter pursued a vegetarian diet. Two years later, a repeat thermal imaging now showed her right breast to have a normal pattern. She was a participant of Project BRCA 6 in August 2004.</string>
    <string name="rosalie">Rosalie F. Cambal -\nAbnormal thermal breast imaging at age 18\n\n\t
Born in Sampaloc, Quezon in 1987, she always had enormously large breasts since high school. Six months before turning 18, she noticed a lump and skin changes on her left breast. Four months after her birthday, her alarmed mother made her undergo a thermal imaging which showed a severely abnormal pattern on the inferior aspect of her left breast. Rosalie has been pursuing non-toxic and non-invasive measures in confronting her breast disorder.</string>
    <string name="bernardita">Bernardita G. De Jesus -\nhormonal reproductive concerns\n\n\t
Born 07 October 1947 in Malabon M.M., Bernie’s menarche was at age 13. With an MBA degree and her last work as Operations Head of a computer data center, she opted for early retirement. She first gave birth at age 26 and less than a year later gave birth to her second child. This prompted her to take pills continuously for the next 6 years. But when she stopped because she wanted to have a 3rd child, she experienced tremendous reproductive problems in the next seven years: prolonged bleeding upon menstruation; several blighted ovum, five D and C’s and a miscarriage in1987 before she had a successful pregnancy at age 39 and gave birth in 1988. Sadly, her infant daughter died 18 months later. She opted for a detoxification to prevent affliction with breast cancer.</string>
    <string name="rosalisa">Rosalisa K. Alindahao -\nDiagnosed at age 42\n\n\t
Born on 14 December 1961 in Paco, Manila, her menarche was at age 12. At age 4, she suffered from asthma and received continuous medications. With an M.S. Degree in Economics, Shalee has been in the banking industry ever since. She started taking birth control pills intermittently at age 27 over a 10-year period.  She gave birth by cesarean section to all of her four children at ages 29, 30, 37 and 39. At the onset of her 2nd pregnancy, she experienced gestational diabetes. The longest breastfed was her 3rd child for a period of six months and the shortest was her eldest at only two weeks. Her first born died at an early age and deeply depressed her for a long period.  Four months before her 43rd birthday, she felt a lump in her right breast. A clinical breast exam was said to be benign but a mammogram and ultrasound done were suspicious for malignancy. A biopsy was then done and malignancy was confirmed. A mastectomy was promptly performed two weeks later and diagnosed with Stage 2A breast cancer with none of 13 lymph nodes recovered found positive. Two months later, she was told that she had brain metastasis. Alarmed and confused, she held off chemotherapy and sought other options. A thermal imaging done showed a severely abnormal pattern on her right post- mastectomy site. Shalee has since been pursuing non-toxic and non-invasive measures in confronting breast cancer. Shalee was a participant of Project BRCA 7 on October 2004. </string>
    <string name="ma_cristina">Ma. Cristina Latosa Bonina -\nDiagnosed at age 39\n\n\t
Born 04 February 1970 in Tatay, Rizal, her menarche was at the late age of 17. Her elementary and secondary years were in Lucena City while she took college in Puerto Princessa City. At age 26, she entered the Order of the Missionaries of the Holy Spirit in Bataan. She first noticed a small lump in her left breast at age 29 but was told by her superiors not to mind it. For the next ten years, the lump persisted and grew until it became itchy and when she scratched it, a wound resulted with a foul smell. Only then did her superiors have her seek medical consultation but Sister Cristina opted to pursue a non-toxic and non-invasive regimen as recommended by a friend-nun of hers who has been living with breast cancer for ten years without having undergone conventional medical treatments. Sister Cristina’s BC risk exposures were most likely her late menarche; irregular menstruation when she entered the convent due to manual laundry with intensive use of chlorox; her diet of donated canned goods and instant noodle and drinking the ground water from an area of large mango orchards regularly sprayed with chemicals. </string>
    <string name="marcelina">Marcelina S. Coloma –\nDiagnosed at age 44\n\n\t
        Born on 30 October 1957 in Loay, Bohol, her menarche was at age 13. A practicing optometrist, she was prescribed Clomid  in her desire to bear child. At age 42, she gave birth to her only child by cesarean section. Twenty months later, she felt a lump in her left breast. The result of a biopsy done was mucinous carcinoma. Two weeks later, she was rushed by her doctor for a mastectomy without discussing her biopsy result. She insisted to have it read first but her doctor said it could wait. After the operation, she was wondering why her doctor didn’t give much concern about the result. Unsatisfied with no explanations given her, she did her own research and learned that her lump was of the benign type and a simple lumpectomy could have been done. Three months later. she underwent a thermal imaging, which showed a severely abnormal pattern on her left post-mastectomy site. A repeat thermal imaging done a year later showed a persistent severely abnormal pattern. A third thermal imaging done another year later still showed the same findings. </string>
    <string name="juanita">Juanita dela Cruz  -\nDiagnosed at age 38\n\n\t
Born on 1 November 1964 in Benito Soliven, Isabela, her menarche was at age 13. Though born deaf and mute, Juanita was able to finish high school and for 5 years, worked as a re-packer of chemicals and fertilizers in an agricultural seed company. She had childbirth at ages 24, 28, 30 and 31 – her third were twins. Eight months after her last childbirth she already felt pain on her right breast but disregarded it. Thrice, she took “cytotec’ (a drug made by G.D.Searle, the same manufacturers of spironolactone) that induced abortion when she got pregnant at ages 34, 36 and 37. By this time, a lump had already grown in her right breast. Upon the advice of her American school teacher, she underwent thermal imaging, which showed an abnormal pattern on her right breast.  </string>
    <string name="helen">Helen G. Valentin -\nDiagnosed at age 48\n\n\t
        Born 1n 1959 in Silay, Negros Occidental, Helen was orphaned at an early age and grew up with relatives in Altavas, Aklan where she was only able to finish high school. Married at age 24, she gave birth a year later and less than 6 months later went to Hong Kong as a domestic helper in 1984. Employed by a Swiss national, she was allowed yearly vacations and would take oral contraceptives before flying home. She continued this practice for the next five years and by 1989, Helen already noticed recurring heat on her left breast but a mammogram done was negative. By this time, she was longing to have another baby and true enough, when she did not take the pill on her return in 1990, she got pregnant and gave birth to another son a year later.  On February 2007 a biopsy was positive for Infiltrating Mucinous Carcinoma.  With the assistance of her former Swiss employer, she went to Tiaong Breast Haven and has since pursued alternative treatments. </string>
    <string name="annaliza">Annaliza Vibal-Alviar\n(20 May 1966 – 07 March 2009)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 41 and died 15 months later. A native of Los Banos, Laguna, her menarche was a age 12. Her entire family had long been drinking ground water (highly suspected of contamination due to their proximity to Laguna de Bay and from the rust of their pump) and only when the town water system was installed in the late ‘80s did they shift to chlorinated tap water. Anna was an elementary school teacher for a total of16 years and experienced required annual chest X-ray when she became a public school teacher at age 30.  She got pregnant a year later but sadly experienced a 2-month term miscarriage and never got pregnant since and failed to undergo a D and C. At age 38, during her annual medical examination required of all public school teachers, she had five chest X-rays within one week because the technician had to keep repeating the procedure until an acceptable X-ray was done.  Two years later, she noticed a lump and the result of a biopsy performed was positive. From that time onwards, she underwent numerous scans, x-rays and other diagnostic procedures because of her health card. However, most tests showed negative results and she was placed under observation and monitoring until the lump got bigger and bigger. Frustrated especially that her card limit had been reached, Anna decided not to go back to her doctor and opted for a non-toxic and non-invasive approach to her dilemma.       </string>
    <string name="teresita">Teresita Q. Bajao\n(06 May 1953 – August 2008)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 53 and died 2 years later. A native of Bilar, Bohol, her menarche was at age13. However, Babes experienced menstruation only once a year, every November. Always, two months prior, she would experience cramps on her right leg and pain on her right abdominal side. At age 16, she was made to take hormonal pills to regulate her cycle but without the knowledge of her physician and parents, took it only for two months because she did not want to experience the monthly difficulties she saw from other girls. Upon finishing her B.S. degree in Pharmacy, she operated a drugstore. About a year after her marriage at age 27, she gave birth to her first child but was only able to breast feed for a month. She was then only able to menstruate for 3 consecutive months and after which, was back to an annual menstruation until she became pregnant with her 2nd child two years later. Thereafter, her menstruation was again once a year until age 42 when it became monthly. Five years later, it became 4 times a year and 3 years later, twice a year. Her 2nd eldest sister was diagnosed at age 45 with breast cancer 20 years after relocating to Chicago and who died a year after surgery and chemotherapy. Her 5th elder sister was diagnosed at age 51 with breast cancer after 20 years after relocating to New Jersey. Both worked in hospitals, the former as a medical technologist and the latter, as a graveyard nurse. At age 52, Babes felt a lump in her right breast but it was only after 7 months that she had a mammogram done, which was suspicious for malignancy and a biopsy confirmed ductal carcinoma. Grade 1. She was then made to undergo a chest x-ray and CT-Scan in preparation for breast surgery and chemotherapy. It was this point that she started searching for an alternative approach, not wanting to experience the toxic and invasive procedures done on her sisters and others she saw. She underwent a thermal imaging, which showed an abnormal pattern on her right breast. With the full support of her husband and children, Babes embarked on a non-conventional and non-traditional regimen to confront her condition.</string>
    <string name="anna">Anna Maria D. Berio\n(28 November 1955 - 17 April 2005)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 47 and died 2 years later. Born in San Carlos City, Negros Occidental, Anna gave birth to two children. She was a Senior Customer Service Officer of the local water district. On May, 2003 she had  mastectomy , followed by  6 cycles of chemotherapy from June to October and finally 25 days of radiation from November to December.  She was able to participate in the PBCNs Project BRCA  7 from 21-25 October 2004 in Tiaong Breast Haven. Nene will always be remembered for her remark, “Wan Toy,” which in her native Ilonggo tongue means, “one breast.” She also shared how she used a condom filled with water to place in the right side of her bra instead of the expensive prosthesis. She was hoping to organize patients in her locality.  </string>
    <string name="ma_victoria">Ma. Victoria M. Cailao\n(10 February 1963 - 2005)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 40 and died 2 years later. Born in Macabebe, Pampanga, her menarche was at age 14. Marivic finished only high school and worked as a caddie for 20 years in the Ayala Golf and Country Club. She first noticed a lump in her left breast at age 34 but upon excision was found to be negative. Three years later, a lump recurred in the same site but she did not give it further thought until another three years when she noticed a discharge. Upon the prodding of a regular female golfer of hers, she underwent a mastectomy at age 40 and was diagnosed with Stage 3B breast cancer with 2/3 lymph nodes positive. Eight months later, she underwent chemotherapy, followed by radiation another 7 months later. Ever since her mastectomy in 2003, she has been suffering from lymph edema and never was she told how to manage it. Desperation drove her to seek help from all her golfing clients and pursue alternative means but only to submit once again to another round of chemotherapy upon the insistence of her female benefactor. </string>
    <string name="patria">Patria Angelica Ledesma-Jimenez\n(4 June 1950 – 1 September 2006)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 53, died 3 years later. Born on in Zamboanga City, her menarche was at age 14. Though not having been able to finish college, she was able to work as a clerk at the City Treasurers Office. Patsy gave birth to 4 children at ages 20, 23, 27 and 31.  Upon the same time that she was experiencing menopause at age 51, she noticed a lump on her right breast. She took it simply as being due to hormonal changes in her system. Two years later, the lump had increased in size. She sought medical attention and a biopsy done was positive for malignancy. A few weeks later, she underwent a mastectomy and was diagnosed with Stage 2B breast cancer. Chemotherapy followed but she discontinued after only two sessions because of intolerable side effects. Two months later, she underwent thermal imaging, which showed a severely abnormal pattern on her right post-mastectomy site. She opted for non-toxic and non-invasive measures in confronting breast cancer. A repeat thermal imaging five months later showed less heat on the affected area. Patsy devoted the rest of her life in reaching out to others when she became active in the Western Mindanao Breast Cancer Action in Zamboanga City. She helped in holding the PBCNs Project BRCA 8 from 19-21 November 2004 in Zamboanga City. </string>
    <string name="julie">Julie B. Acuña\n(04 February 1953 – August 2008)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 45 and died 10 years later. Born on 4 February 1953 in Ozamis City, her menarche was at age 12. Julie gave birth at ages 24, 25, 31 and 37- the last by caesarian section. A dedicated public school teacher, it was on October 1997 that she first felt a lump on right breast. After a mammogram and ultrasound, she underwent frozen section on May 1998 in Davao without her consent. Diagnosed with IDC Stage III, chemo June-July, only 2 sessions due to financial constraints. 2000 recurrence and underwent 3 cycles of chemo. 2001, noted a small nodule. In 2003, it had enlarged. June-August, underwent radiation therapy. In 2006, she finally went to Tiaong Breast Haven On December the dame year, she organized a 2-day  PBCN symposium in Cotabato City with the help of her church members. </string>
    <string name="theodora">Theodora F. Cruz\n(15 December 1934 – 4 April 2005)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 66 and died 4 years later. Born in Paco, Manila, her menarche was at age 12. Not able to finish her high school, she remained a child-free woman and became a government employee until retirement. At age 66, she felt a lump on her left breast. She was immediately submitted to frozen section biopsy and a mastectomy was done. She was diagnosed with Stage 3 breast cancer. Thereafter, she suffered from lymph edema on her left arm.</string>
    <string name="concepcion">Concepcion G. Cutay\n(18 Sep 1964 – 22 Jan 2011)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 36 and died 10 years later. Born in Los Baños, Laguna, her menarche was at age 12. Connie finished her Masters Degree in Development Communication at the University of the Philippines. She gave birth to her only child at age 26, whom she breastfed for 18 months. Ten years later, she noticed a lump on her right breast. Both mammogram and ultrasound results done at one of the country’s premier private hospital showed suspicions of lobular carcinoma in situ. A week later, an excision biopsy done was positive for ductal carcinoma. Four weeks later, she underwent a mastectomy and was diagnosed with Stage 1 breast cancer. A month later, she under went 6-cycles of chemotherapy. Thinking she was doing fine, she was surprised two months later to learn that her thermal imaging showed a severely abnormal pattern on her post-mastectomy site. Connie then pursed non-toxic and non-invasive regimens for nine years.  </string>
    <string name="ma_asuncion">Ma. Asuncion G. Gregorio\n(11 May 1961 – 20 March 2009)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 39 and died 9 years later. Born in  Zamboanga City, her menarche was at age 13. Darling gave birth at a very early age of 20 and has been a single parent since then. At age 39, she noticed a lump on her right breast. A biopsy was done 4 months later and was diagnosed to have Stage 2 breast cancer. She underwent a lumpectomy, followed by a mastectomy a month later but of the 12 lymph nodes recovered, none were found to be positive. Upon medical advice, she underwent chemotherapy for 3 months. Thereafter, she was prescribed Tamoxifen for the next five years, but which she took for only a month due to the side effects she experienced. In her search to address her condition, she was able to get in contact with the PBCN and underwent a Thermal Imaging 8 months later, which showed a severe abnormality on her post-mastectomy site. A repeat thermal done 6 months later still showed persistence of the severe abnormality. Darling had since chosen to pursue a strict nutritional and detoxification regimen in confronting her health condition.  Darling witnessed the start of construction of Tiaong Breast Haven in 2002. She also participated in the first Project BRCA on 25-27 October 2002. Darling later organized on 18-21 November 2004 , Project BRCA 8 in Zamboanga City. A few months before she passed away, she brought her Aunt Lety Jotie  to Tiaong Breast Haven. </string>
    <string name="jane">Jane F. Javier\n(22 Oct 1971 - 07 June 2012)\n\n\t
Diagnosed at age 33 and died  8 years later. From Gen. Natividad in Nueva Ecija, Jane was a very dedicated public school teacher. Her case was a non-aggressive cancer that became aggressive. She underwent mastectomy, chemo and radiation in 2004 and thinking she was cured, Jane carried on her old ways until 7 years later when she had a recurrence. She again underwent surgery mid-2011 but was now told that her cancer had already spread. This time, she refused chemo and sought out the PBCN. Strongly advised to resign from her job and concentrate on her health, she felt that her young students needed her and back to work she did when she felt better after the PBCNs protocol. By the end of classes last March, she started experiencing breathing difficulties. It may be said that she surpassed the 5-year survival rate after chemo but on the other hand, she was only Stage 1 in 2004.  </string>
    <string name="ana">Breast Cancer Survivor Ana Juanillo –\n25 Years in Remission\n\n\t
Ms. Ana Juanillo was 40 years old in 1990 when I did a modified radical mastectomy on her breast cancer in the Philippine General Hospital.  There was no postoperative adjuvant treatment whatsoever.   She is now 65 years old. She is now in remission for 25 years.  We both thank God for this long remission.</string>
    <string name="mercy">Breast Cancer Survivor Mercy Redona –\n14 Years in Remission\n\n\t
Ms. Mercy Redona was 57 years old in 2000 when I operated on her breast cancer – modified radical mastectomy.  She received 6 cycles of chemotherapy (CMF) because of 6 positive axillary nodes.  She had local recurrence 9 years after the operation.  She was treated for this.  As of December 2014, she is 14 years in remission.  We both thank God for this long remission.</string>
    <string name="richilda">Breast Cancer Survivor Richilda Durano –\n10 Years in Remission\n\n\t
Ms. Richilda Durano from Cotabato City had a breast cancer for which I did a modified radical mastectomy in March 13, 2004 in Manila Doctors Hospital.    Breast cancer mass was 3 cm and axillary nodes were negative for spread.  She did not receive any adjuvant treatment after the operation.  I saw her recently when she came to me for her annual check-up.  She is now 61  years old  and 10 years in remission.  We both thank God for this long remission.</string>
    <string name="lily">Breast Cancer Survivor Lily Tolentino –\n10 Years in Remission\n\n\t
Ms. LilyTolentino underwent modified radical mastectomy for her breast cancer on October 27, 2004.  October 27, 2014 marks her 10th year in remission and she went to St. Jude Church on that day to say thank you to God and St. Jude.  She came to see me on October 28, 2014 to tell me that she has reached her 10-year target and that I should include her in my cancer survivor registry.  She gave me a thank you note.  We both thank God for this long remission.</string>
    <string name="bibiana">Breast Cancer Survivor Bibiana Gutierrez –\n17 Years in Remission\n\n\t
In 1997, Ms. Bibiana Gutierrez was 47 years old when she got a cancer on her right breast. She underwent a modified radical mastectomy in Manila Doctors Hospital. The histopathologic result was invasive ductal carcinoma with negative nodal spread. She did not receive additional treatment after the operation. She is now 65 years old (2014) and 17 years in remission. We both thank God for this long remission.</string>


    <string-array name="classification">
        <item>Early Intervention</item>
        <item>Living with Breast Cancer</item>
        <item>Recurrence/Metastasis</item>
        <item>Prevention is the Cure!</item>
        <item>Cancer Survivors</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="namesEI">
        <item>Norie G. Aguilo</item>
        <item>Placida C. Babao</item>
        <item>Marivic N. Belleza</item>
        <item>Rosalie F. Cambal</item>
        <item>Bernardita G. De Jesus</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="namesLwBC">
        <item>Rosalisa K. Alindahao</item>
        <item>Ma. Cristina Latosa Bonina</item>
        <item>Marcelina S. Coloma</item>
        <item>Juanita dela Cruz</item>
        <item>Helen G. Valentin</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="namesRM">
        <item>Annaliza Vibal-Alviar</item>
        <item>Teresita Q. Bajao</item>
        <item>Anna Maria D. Berio</item>
        <item>Ma. Victoria M. Cailao</item>
        <item>Patria Angelica Ledesma-Jimenez </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="namesPitC">
        <item>Julie B. Acuña</item>
        <item>Theodora F. Cruz</item>
        <item>Concepcion G. Cutay</item>
        <item>Ma. Asuncion G. Gregorio</item>
        <item>Jane F. Javier</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="namesCS">
        <item>Ana Juanillo</item>
        <item>Mercy Redona</item>
        <item>Richilda Durano</item>
        <item>Lily Tolentino</item>
        <item>Bibiana Gutierrez</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_norie">norie</string>
    <string name="title_activity_placida">placida</string>
    <string name="title_activity_marivic">marivic</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rosalie">rosalie</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bernardita">bernardita</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rosalisa">rosalisa</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ma_cristina">ma_cristina</string>
    <string name="title_activity_marcelina">marcelina</string>
    <string name="title_activity_juanita">juanita</string>
    <string name="title_activity_helen">helen</string>
    <string name="title_activity_annaliza">annaliza</string>
    <string name="title_activity_teresita">teresita</string>
    <string name="title_activity_anna">anna</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ma_victoria">ma_victoria</string>
    <string name="title_activity_patria">patria</string>
    <string name="title_activity_julie">julie</string>
    <string name="title_activity_theodora">theodora</string>
    <string name="title_activity_concepcion">concepcion</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ma_ascuncion">ma_ascuncion</string>
    <string name="title_activity_jane">jane</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ana">ana</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mercy">mercy</string>
    <string name="title_activity_richilda">richilda</string>
    <string name="title_activity_lily">lily</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bibiana">bibiana</string>


</resources>
